Every 4 years, Bitcoin does the same
exact moves. It shocks everybody, but
not anymore. Take a look. The Stochastic
RSI just went below this historic level
of this white line right here. And when
it does, it gets ugly. It gets gruesome,
and it's always for the same amount of
time. Take a look. 2022 was the previous
time we dipped below here, and that was
when the market started to crash, and it
took over 424
days [music] to recover. The time before
then was 4 years earlier, 2018. Dip
below this level in the white line, and
it was an absolute bloodbath for almost
days to recover. Time before then,
exactly 4 years earlier, 2014. Dip below
this level in the Stochastic RSI, and it
was an absolute bloodbath, but this time
took [music] 579
days to recover. The first ever time was
in 2011, dipping below here, and it was
just 335
days to recover. So, what are we doing
to do now? What is about to happen in
the market? I need to explain it to you.
I need to explain what it's looking like
for the recovery, and we're going to
give a very huge clue to the next cycle
top, because the next cycle top is going
to be an absolute devastation, and I
need to give you another hidden clue
right inside of this chart. So, let's
get into it. By the way, we are getting
tons of comments about when bottom and
altcoins. Did you know I give my top
altcoin picks and my big secret
investment both covered in the Bitcoin
Bottom Blueprint. Just my big secret
investment alone is already worth
multiple times the cost of the Bitcoin
Bottom Blueprint. But on top of that,
you get my top altcoin picks. And on top
of that, you get one guaranteed buy
inside of the golden zone or your money
back. Public launch coming soon. Watch
your email.
Right now, we're on the Bitcoin US
dollar index, and today we are on the
monthly chart. On the monthly chart, we
have price action above our heads, and
below we have the stochastic RSI, which
measures our momentum and goes from
range of zero up to a range of 100.
Simply put, when we are up here in this
highway between these yellow lines,
that's when you want to take profit. And
you want to buy when we are below this
white line. But more specifically, I'm
going to give you some hidden clues as
to know when to pull the trigger. Let's
start our journey with take a mental
snapshot of what the market is looking
like right now. Because a few weeks to a
month ago, everybody was getting
excited, but we had shown this chart
right here, and we said, "Look, we've
got to give credit to this chart. We're
supposed to stay level-headed. We're
below this white line, and it's going to
take couple hundred days to recover."
Everybody thought it would be very, very
quick, and sure enough, the facts played
out. Let's start our journey back in
2011. You see this anomaly. The first
time that we went below this level, it
was only 335 days to recover. Not too
shabby. But we're measure it based on
when the orange line goes below and when
the orange line goes back above. In
other words, the stochastic RSI is made
up of two lines, the blue line and the
orange. When the blue is on top, price
goes up. When the orange is on top,
price goes down. In other words, when
the orange is on top, our momentum is
heading down, so price goes down. And
when blue is on top, our momentum is
heading up, so price goes up. It's very
simple and very powerful. And on the
monthly chart, it eliminates all the
noise, eliminates a lot of the
guesswork, and you just are left with
pure bonafide facts, which help you stay
level-headed. When you look at the first
example, 335, you look at the longest
example, 579, what I'm going to do today
is show you the range. The range at what
it's looking like, when this thing will
recover, because the same patterns
repeat every single time. As soon as
this orange line comes back up above
this white line, it's game on. It's the
bull run, it is time for prices to
explode. First example is 335, second
579, third was just under 400, and the
last example we have 424. What you want
to notice is that the stochastic RSI
will tell you everything that you need
to know about the market. I want you to
stay more level-headed than you normally
stay, and I want you to understand one
thing, money always moves from impatient
hands to patient hands. That's how it's
been for the history of mankind, expect
that trend to continue. In other words,
I want you to be more patient. I want
you to trade way less. Everybody's going
to make it seem in social media land
they should be trading more. Oh my god,
there's this big opportunity, there's
this big thing happening, you need to be
in this trade, you need to be out of
this trade, you need to short this, you
need to long this, you need to leverage
this, you need to do this, you need to
be out of this, you need to this new
altcoin. I want you to take all of that
and throw it in the trash, because the
truth is, the facts are, you should
actually trade a lot less. In fact, the
right thing to do most often when you
have a thought in your mind, oh my god,
I need to buy, I need to sell, I need to
most often, the best thing to do,
nothing. Don't do anything. And I want
you to spend way more time studying the
bottom golden zone window and the top
zone window. Those are the two windows I
want you to operate in every couple
years. I don't want you to make any more
trades, and when you do that, you'll
have way more success, and you'll be
like, why didn't I know this 10 years
ago? Back to this chart. When the
momentum gets below this level right
here, this white level that's about 17,
that's when we lose all of our momentum.
In other words, we run out of momentum.
And what happens when you have no
momentum to go up? You go down. When our
momentum goes below this level, that's
when the worst moves happen. The
bloodbath really happens during this
400-ish day window. In other words,
every bottom of the market happened
below here when we are out of momentum.
And simply put, when our momentum goes
back up, it's time to buy. It's time to
get back into the market to ride that
next wave up for the next couple years,
and then to look for that window to take
profits, which the profit window is this
road up here. What you notice about this
time, this time was a little bit
different. You see, we had that cross
after 400-ish days back in January 2023.
In January 2023, we started to come up
with this orange line. We started to
create that beginning of the bull run.
And from that point, we rallied beyond
belief in our stochastic RSI. In other
words, we went way up into this top
zone, and we went all the way to the
tippity tippity top. And I showed you
this on the monthly chart back in the
Christmas time 2023 and early 2024. And
we just said, "It's not sustainable. Our
momentum cannot sustain here, and what's
likely going to happen is we're going to
have a lower high." In other words,
we're going to start creating bearish
divergence. And we started watching this
bearish divergence form. And we went
from our first swing high in February 24
to our next swing low was a lower high
back in January 25, and it was another
lower high. We had another high, but it
was another lower high for the third
consecutive time. In other words, we had
price going up while our indicator was
going down. That is classic bearish
divergence. And when that breaks, you
often see it snap break, and price
usually reflects that. But, what you'll
notice that happened is something very
interesting. Because when this broke at
126,000,
we plummeted in price, we dropped below
finally in this level here, January
2026, having the orange line drop below
here, starting our countdown timer of
roughly 400 days, which we'll get to in
a moment. And by the way, in this video,
I want to tell you what I think is going
to happen next, and what I think you
should do with the information that I'm
sharing with you in this video. And then
also, I want to drop another big clue
about the next market cycle top. And
this one might be a little bit
controversial. Recently, many of you
have been randomly unsubscribed from my
channel. And missing just one video in a
market like this can cost you big time.
So, stop what you're doing, look down,
and make sure you are subscribed. What
we have on our hands is we had that
bearish divergence break, 126,000. Price
plummet, momentum plummet, drop below
this level, and then we saw a rebound.
We saw a cross back up, and this is what
threw everybody off. But, we had been
doing this pattern for a couple years
now, so we were just doing more of the
same. We like to have our momentum
plummet, then a slight rebound, momentum
plummet again, slight rebound, momentum
plummet again. So, that's what we did.
We had a little rebound, people got
excited, but we remained level-headed
with this chart. And credit goes to this
chart, because we pulled up this chart,
we talked about it, you and I, and we
said, "Look, we can't get overly
excited." Everybody was getting excited
about 80-something thousand-dollar
Bitcoin, but we had already fallen into
the trap. We knew it was going to be 400
days before this thing got better. And
everybody overreacted when we were in
the '80s, and the rest is history. What
happens next? Because what happens next
is likely going to be more of the same.
And I want to paint a picture of what if
it's only 330 days? And what if it's
almost 600 days? What will that look
like? So, let's get to the 330 days. 330
days from that point, you're looking at
roughly the end of 2026. In other words,
this could come as soon as the end of
2026. According to the data that we have
in front of us, it would be absolutely
ludicrous to say that that's not a
possibility. We quite literally have
facts that that is a possibility. So,
the end of 2026 would be the earliest
that we could see this start to turn a
corner. But, that's the earliest. What
about the latest? The latest is 579
days. Where does that bring us? That
brings us until August of 2027. In other
words, we have the end of this year
until August of 2027. During that
period, the data suggests it will fall
in line. Now, what is the most likely
outcome? Well, if you look at the data
in front of us, around 400-ish days is a
likely scenario that has played out
multiple times, especially the past 8
years. So, what is likely to happen? If
that were the case, roughly 400-ish
days, you're looking at roughly the Q1
of 2027. Q1 of 2027 is the most likely
culprit to be the beginning of the bull
in the end of the devastation, and the
bottom will be fully locked in by that
time, and the bull run will be just in
its infancy stages in Q1 2027. Now, what
should you do with this information? And
more importantly, what's this big clue
about the next bull run? What's this big
warning about the next bull run? I want
to get into that. What we have on our
hands here is two things. Number one, we
want to talk about what should you do
with this information? What I want you
to do is be way more patient. I want you
to trade way less. I want you to focus
on the bottom golden zone window for the
rest of this year. Focus on the bottom
golden zone window. And that's the
window to really maximize your profits.
And it's likely going to happen from
sometime now until sometime by the end
of the year. And likely in Q1, we will
move into this new phase where the
market starts to shift and will be very,
very slight. It'll catch a lot of people
by surprise. Nobody will want to believe
it because they'll all think we're going
a lot lower and we will start to rise in
prices. But this next run will be unlike
anything we've seen before. And I
alluded to it in other videos and we
talked a lot about it in our previous
video and I want to drop another clue.
So, what did we say in the previous
video? It's million-dollar Bitcoin is
almost a lock for 2030 according to a
lot of really smart people and a lot of
huge institutions. It's a very common
for million-dollar Bitcoin by 2030.
You've seen it everywhere. But I'm here
to tell you based on the facts that is
highly unlikely to happen. It would be
an absolute shock for that to happen. In
fact, I'll take it a step further, which
I showed you in the last video, it's
likely that even half a million-dollar
Bitcoin is not going to happen in the
next cycle. And I'll drop another huge
clue and it has a lot to do with what
I've been talking about for years and
years and years. Every single cycle is
getting weaker and weaker and weaker.
Don't take my word for it, look at the
facts. The first cycle, this percentage
gain was never seen again. The next
cycle was a lot smaller by a big factor.
In other words, this move back in 2010
all the way up to 2011, we never saw
that percentage gain again. It's never
happened in all of the years since. In
fact, the next cycle from here in
November 2011 up to the top of 2013,
that percentage gain was also never seen
again because it was way smaller than
the first percentage gain and still it
was never seen again. And the next
percentage gain in 2017 was also never
seen again. And it was also smaller than
the previous one by a wide margin, which
the previous one was way smaller than
the first one by a wide margin. Do you
see a trend? Because I tried to tell
everybody this years ago and not a lot
of people wanted to listen. Everybody
was like, "Are you crazy?" Like in this
past cycle, it was almost a guarantee
that we would see quarter million dollar
Bitcoin. And I tried to almost guarantee
that it would we wouldn't see quarter
million dollar Bitcoin, definitely half
a million dollar A lot of people were
saying half a million dollar Bitcoin,
but I mean the proof is in the pudding.
So, each cycle is getting weaker and
weaker and each cycle percentage gain we
have never seen again. And I just want
to point out the percentage gain from
last cycle. Let's just go and look at
it. So, from the bottom of the market
all the way to the top, you know, we're
looking at about 700%.
Expect us never to see that for this
next cycle. However, I do have some good
news. I think what's going to happen is
we're going to go through a rough period
in Bitcoin, which is what we've seen the
stock market do for over a hundred
years. Like every 30-ish years
there's a 10-year period of devastation,
a bloodbath, and then the cycle will
repeat. In other words, this is sort of
one cycle, okay? All these years of
Bitcoin that we've had since the start
is one whole cycle. And I think that
rough cycle is going to repeat after a
10-year devastation cycle. In other
words, what I just described is like 40
years into the future. That's what I
think is going to happen. I think we're
in the beginning of this devastation
period, and a lot of people will give up
on Bitcoin, and a lot of people will go
away from Bitcoin, but the
infrastructure won't change, and the
smart people will still be here
building, and Bitcoin will have this
growth phase after that 10-year period,
and it'll be something similar to this
cycle that we just had, but probably not
to that extreme. And that's roughly how
I think the next 30-ish years are going
to play out. By the way, we are getting
tons of comments about when bottom and
altcoins. Did you know I give my top
altcoin picks and my big secret
investment, both covered in the Bitcoin
Bottom Blueprint? Just my big secret
investment alone is already worth
multiple times the cost of the Bitcoin
Bottom Blueprint. But on top of that,
you get my top altcoin picks, and on top
of that, you get one guaranteed buy
inside of the golden zone, or your money
back. Public launch coming soon. Watch
your email.